Rahul Nair

🗣 Bengaluru, Karnataka, India 🖿 nair.rahul5681@gmail.com 🔲 +919980898206 🔚 in/rahul-nair-156bba4b/

SUMMARY

SEO Specialist with 6 years of experience in all aspects of SEO, including on-page, off-page, keyword analysis, and link building. Proven ability to analyze and improve organic traffic and outreach efforts. Experience in digital marketing, branding, and new business strategy across multiple industries.

EXPERIENCE

SEO Specialist

Webnine Solutions

February 2022 - Present, Bengaluru

- · Devised and implemented robust digital acquisition plans, ensuring precision with reporting, budgets, and re-forecasts.
- Manage digital SERP streaming accounts to improve brand positioning and growth.
- · Research SEO keywords to use throughout the company's website and marketing materials.
- Source and develop new strategic partnerships, social engagements, and advertising opportunities that generate new revenue streams.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Increased conversion rates by 15\% + on client's web-based service offering through SEO Strategies}.$

Marketing Executive

Stalkus Digital

January 2021 - February 2022, Bengaluru

- · Boosted Google SERP rankings for clients through the creation of informative, high-quality organic content for company blogs, websites, and social media accounts.
- \cdot Conducted keyword research in order to identify high-volume keywords to target, negative keywords to avoid, and an analysis of competitor's keyword rankings.
- · Facilitated a successful rebrand campaign focused on refreshing and repositioning a client's brand.

Marketing Manager

Vasp Information Technology

March 2018 - January 2021, Bengaluru

- Developed/implemented SEO recommendations that improved SERP.
- · Developing e-commerce strategy & supporting the business in implementing it.
- Developed & applied strategic digital marketing plans to drive key marketing metrics.
- · Deployed specific tactics to support the overall strategy and help achieve desired results.
- · Growth hacking, A/B testing, PPC, email campaigns.

Executive Operations

Flipkart

August 2017 - March 2018, Bengaluru

- · Undertake sensitive and confidential liaison on behalf of the Manager with senior staff, industry and commercial partners of the company.
- · Joined new pro escalation team to deliver the high level issues with prime customers and clients.
- · Analysed and reported critical issues on escalation.

Ir. Accountant

Cohera Automations

March 2016 - April 2017, Bengaluru

- · Maintained Companies daily working P&L, Balance sheet.
- · Reporting inventory moments.
- · Cost cutting for transport and handling.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Business Management

Minor in Marketing • Amrita University • Mysore • 2015 • 6.7

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified SEO for Social Media

LinkedIn · 2022

Marketing & Retail Analytics - Advanced

Great Learning · 2022

SEO Strategies

Great Learning · 2022

Advance Google analytics

LinkedIn · 2022

Advanced SEO: Search Factors

LinkedIn · 2022

Programmatic Advertising Foundations

LinkedIn ⋅ 2022

Google Ads Display Certification

Google Digital Academy · 2022

Google Digital Garage Certification

Google Skill shop · 2021

Google My Business Optimisation

Google Skill Shop · 2021

The Ultimate SEO Training 2022 + SEO For Wordpress Websites

Udemy • 2021

Digital Marketing

Udemy · 2021

Certified SEO Masterclass

SEMLY Pro · 2021

Google Analytics Certifications

Udemy · 2019

Certificate of Merit Tech-Ad event

Amrita University • 2014

Certificate in Computer Application

2010

SKILLS

Google Analytics

Google Search Console

SEMrush

Tableau public

Google Ads

Facebook Insights

Facebook Creative Tool

Wordpress

Local SEO

Email Marketing

Data Studio

Ahrefs

MS office

Screaming Frog

Hosting and Server